sproutinc.com 2011-05-15

# Sprout » Privacy Policy

Last Updated: October 15, 2010

**Sprout Privacy Policy**

Chipin, Inc., dba “Sprout” (“Sprout”) provides this Privacy Policy to inform you of our policies and procedures regarding the collection, use and disclosure of personal information we receive when you visit and use the www.sproutinc.com site (the “Site”) and when you use our services (including widgets generated via our services) and software via our Site or on the websites of our partners or other third parties (collectively, the “Services”).

This Privacy Policy applies only to information that you provide to us through our Services (including that which we may collect on your behalf). The term “End User” as used in this Privacy Policy means a visitor to or user of a widget that was created with or includes the Services.  If you are an End User please note that the information you provide to us may be shared with the Sprout user running our Services.  We recommend that you see the privacy policies of such Sprout user (including that of the website where you are interacting with a Sprout generated widget) for information regarding their privacy practices.

This Privacy Policy may be updated from time to time.  We will notify you of any material changes by posting the new Privacy Policy on the Site.  You are advised to consult this Privacy Policy regularly for any changes.

**Information We Collect**

Personal Information. In the course of using the Services, we may ask you to provide us with certain personally identifiable information that can be used to contact you, identify you, and/or administer your account (“Personal Information”).  Personal Information may include, but is not limited to, your name, phone number, credit card or other billing information, email address and home and business postal addresses.

Log Data. When you use the Services, our servers automatically record information that your browser sends whenever you visit a website or online service (“Log Data”).  This Log Data may include, but is not limited to, your computer’s Internet Protocol address, browser type, the web page you were visiting before you came to the Site and information you search for on the Site.

Cookies. Like many websites, we use “cookies” to collect information.  A cookie is a small data file that is delivered through your web browser to your computer’s hard disk for record keeping purposes.  We use cookies (i) to enable certain features of the Services like saving your username and login password for future logins to the Site, (ii) to monitor aggregate usage of the Services and web traffic on the Site to improve our Services and (iii) to track your preferences and usage patterns on the Site, via the Services and on other websites.  “Usage Data” means the information collected through our use of cookies which may be linked to a numbered cookie on a user’s computer.  You can instruct your browser, by changing its options, to stop accepting cookies or to prompt you before accepting a cookie from the websites or services you visit.  If you do not accept cookies, however, you may not be able to use all portions of the Site or all functionality of the Services.

Third party advertisers on the Site or that you interact with through the Services (including any ads or widgets) may also place or read cookies on your computer’s browser, which permit them to collect information about users who view or interact with their advertisements and content. The collection and use of such information is subject to such third party’s privacy policy. Usage Data may also be updated through our Services’ recognition of cookies placed on your computer by third party sites or services.

Pixel Tags. We may also use “pixel tags,” “web beacons,” “clear GIFs” or similar means (individually or collectively “Pixel Tags”) in connection with a Sprout generated widget to, among other things, compile aggregate statistics about use of the Services and to collect gender and geographical location data.  A Pixel Tag is an electronic image, often a single pixel, that is ordinarily not visible to website users and may be associated with cookies on a user’s hard drive. Pixel Tags allow us to count users who have visited certain pages of the Site, to deliver branded services and to help determine the effectiveness of promotional or advertising campaigns.

**Our Policy Toward Children**

Sprout does not knowingly collect personally identifiable information from children under 13.  If a parent or guardian becomes aware that his or her child has provided us with Personal Information without their consent, he or she should contact us at legal@sproutinc.com.  If we become aware that a child under 13 has provided us with Personal Information, we will delete such information from our files.

**How We Use Personal Information**

  * Personal Information is used for the following purposes:  (i) to provide and improve the Services, features and content, (ii) to administer your use of the Services and/or Sprout account, (iii) to enable users to enjoy and easily navigate the Site, (iv) to better understand your needs and interests, (v) to fulfill requests you may make, (vi) to personalize your experience, (vii) to provide service announcements, and (viii) to provide you with further information and offers from us or third parties that we believe you may find useful or interesting, including newsletters, marketing or promotional materials and other information on Sprout related services.  If you are a Sprout Member and decide at any time that you no longer wish to receive such communications listed in item viii, above, please follow the unsubscribe instructions provided in the communication. A “ **Sprout Member** ” is defined as a person or company who has a current Sprout Builder™ account in good standing.

  * We use information we obtain by technical means (such as the automatic recording performed by our servers or through the use of cookies) for the above purposes and in order to monitor and analyze use of the Services and for the technical administration of the Site, to increase the functionality and user-friendliness of the Services, to better tailor both to your needs, to generate and derive useful data and information concerning the interests, characteristics and website use behavior of our users, and to verify that visitors and users to and of the Services meet the criteria required to process their requests.

**Information Sharing and Disclosure**

Registered Sprout Users. In addition to your username, any comments or submissions that you post to the Site or Services will be publicly available. For example, if you are using the social community networking features of our Services hosted by us or a Sprout user running our Services on their website, the information you publish will be viewable by other users.  Any information you choose to provide in a comment or a submission should reflect how much you want other users to know about you.  We recommend that you guard your anonymity and sensitive information and we encourage Sprout users to think carefully about what information about themselves they disclose in their comments or submissions.

End User Information. We may share End User information (including Usage Data) with the Sprout user for whom we collected such information.

Aggregate Information and Non-Identifying Information. We may share aggregated information that includes Usage Data and Log Data with third parties for industry analysis, demographic profiling, and to deliver targeted advertising about other products and services.  Any aggregated information shared in these contexts will not contain your Personal Information.

Service Providers. We may employ third party companies and individuals to facilitate the Services, to provide the Services on our behalf, to perform services related to administration of the Services (including, without limitation, bill and credit card payment processing, maintenance, hosting and database management services, web analytics and administration).  These third parties have access to your Personal Information only to perform these tasks on our behalf and are obligated not to disclose or use it for any other purpose, unless they have your permission.

Compliance with Laws and Law Enforcement. Sprout cooperates with government and law enforcement officials and private parties to enforce and comply with the law.  We will disclose any information about you to government or law enforcement officials or private parties as we, in our sole discretion, believe necessary or appropriate to respond to claims and legal process (including but not limited to subpoenas), to protect the property and rights of Sprout or a third party, to protect the safety of the public or any person, or to prevent or stop any activity we may consider to be, or to pose a risk of being, illegal, unethical, inappropriate or legally actionable.

Business Transfers. In connection with a merger, acquisition, reorganization or sale of assets or in the event of bankruptcy, Sprout may sell, transfer or otherwise share some or all of its assets, including your Personal Information.

**Changing or Deleting Your Information**

All registered Sprout users may review, update, correct or delete the Personal Information in their registration profile by logging into their account and changing the “user preferences” associated with their account.  If you completely delete all such information, your account may be deactivated.  We may retain an archived copy of your records as required by law or for legitimate business purposes.

**Security**

Sprout is concerned with safeguarding your information.  We employ a variety of industry-standard measures designed to protect your information from unauthorized access.

**International Transfer**

Your information may be transferred to – and maintained on – computers located outside of your state, province, country or other governmental jurisdiction where the privacy laws may not be as protective as those in your jurisdiction.  If you are located outside the United States and choose to provide information to Sprout, please be advised that we transfer Personal Information to the United States and process it there.  Your consent to this Privacy Policy followed by your submission of such information represents your agreement to that transfer.

**Links to Other Site**

The Services contain links to other websites.  If you choose to visit an advertiser by “clicking on” a banner ad or other type of advertisement, or click on another third party link, you will be directed to that third party’s website.  The fact that we link to a website or present a banner ad or other type of advertisement is not an endorsement, authorization or representation that we are affiliated with that third party, nor is it an endorsement of their privacy or information security policies or practices.  We do not exercise control over third party websites.  These other websites may place their own cookies or other files on your computer, collect data or solicit personal information from you.  Other websites and services follow different rules regarding the use or disclosure of the personal information you submit to them.  We encourage you to read the privacy policies or statements of the other websites you visit.

**Contacting Us**

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, please contact us at legal [at] sproutinc.com.
